I'm going to be saying a bunch of words
that I don't like. Anyway, the title is
spoton. There are studies that look at a
particular drink and the impact that
drink has on removing toxic pollutants
out of your body. There you go. A few of
the words that I don't like. So, we'll
go over the science, we'll go over the
drink, and we'll go over why some people
might seem genetically screwed, yet this
drink may overcome their genetic faults.
Let's get into it. I've always disliked
using words like toxic and detox and
pollutants because they're incredibly
generic and get thrown around entirely
too much, especially the word cleanse
and detox. But in this instance, there
is some merit because if anything is
going to be called a detox from your
body, it's going to be the molecules
like heavy metals and organic irritants
like different benzines and aldahhides.
You see, when you breathe, especially in
a big city or an industrial area,
microparticles get sucked down your
lungs. And along with those particles
are these irritants and poisons, the
metals and the like that we just
mentioned. These particles are linked to
increased risk of cancer and a host of
other health issues. And some of these
particles can end up in other areas of
your body and even accumulate over time.
So clearly, it seems reasonable to want
to find a solution. Fortunately, our
body is equipped with a solution. It's
called glutathione. This potent protein
or tripeptide can bind pollutants. That
word again with the help of an enzyme
glutathione s transferase or GST. Then
this compound including the toxic
pollutant will be acted on by a series
of enzymes that ultimately metabolize it
to mercapuric acid. This mercapuric acid
can then be excreted in your urine. And
there's ways of increasing this removal
of these pollutants. In one study,
participants were randomly assigned to
consume a detox drink or placebo drink
that looked and tasted identically. Then
the participants consume these drinks
over 12 weeks. And the researchers
measured the urine excretion of some of
these pollutants that we discussed like
benzines. In fact, here are the three
pollutants that they tracked. These are
the measures at baseline. So before
consuming either drink. The main point
of this table is to show that there was
no differences in excretion levels
between the groups initially confirmed
statistically on the right as none of
the values bel fall below 0.05. Okay. So
what happened over the next many weeks
of consuming this detox drink? Well,
look for yourself. We're looking at
benzene, that cancerpromoting pollutant.
And on the vertical axis is the amount
of excretion, while the horizontal is
the days past. So the green squares are
the detox drink. and we're comparing
against the placebo. Clearly, there's a
big difference. In fact, the detox drink
was able to increase benzene removal by
a whopping
60%. Well, what about irritants? Looking
at those data, we see mixed results.
Clearly, acryine is also increased in
its excretion by about 20%. However, if
your eyes go down a bit, you'll note
that the chron
crotonaldahhide
crotonaldahhide, that's a tough one,
does not change, indicating the detox
drink is effective, but selectively so.
So, what's in this
drink? It's broccoli sprouts. More
specifically, as mentioned in this
study, it's likely the molecules
glucaraphin and its product molecule.
Sulfurophane, the active compound is the
second of the two. So, sulfurophane. So,
why do they work? And why do some people
experience better effects than others?
Before that, there's a specific
formulation of the drink that's often
used, and there's even a way to
supercharge its effects by adding an
ingredient to it. If you're interested
in a guide on how to make it, I created
one based on multiple studies that's
available for the Physionic Insiders
along with the extended version of this
video. If you aren't a member, now's
your chance. Let's not forget all the
other perks that come with an insider
membership from live sessions, monthly
private podcasts, access to all other
guides and protocols, research reviews,
and more. It'll help you detox from the
misinformation out there. The link to
join is in the description. Now, how
does sulfurophane work? Well, it works
through a number of ways. One, it can
activate a potent protein in your cells
called NRF2. This protein known as a
transcription factor can enter your
cell's nucleus. There it'll bind to
different antioxidant response elements
that upregulate or increase the reading
of genes that are responsible for the
production of good old glutathione.
Beyond that, a second mechanism is tied
to the enzyme that we briefly discussed,
the GST enzyme that attaches these
pollutants to the glutathione.
Sulfurophane increases the activity of
these enzymes. This in combination leads
to greater mercapuric acid production
and the elimination of these toxins. But
speaking to those enzymes, there's
something else remarkable about this
drink. I mentioned at the beginning of
our time together, by the way, are you
comfortable? Do you need a drink or
anything? Is it like too hot in here?
Yeah, sure. I Yeah, I can turn the AC
up. Just give me a second. So, back to
it. Like I mentioned, there's these
enzymes that conjugate or add these
pollutants to glutathione to begin their
ultimate excretion in urine. However,
some people don't have these enzymes, at
least not functional versions. That's
right. Some people are genetically
screwed in that they don't excrete much
of these pollutants even when they're
exposed to high levels. They're called
GST null
individuals. I don't know why they just
like made me laugh, but they did. U but
I did mention that this detox, so
sulfurophane drink might be able to
overcome this major issue. If we look at
the data, you'll note the amount of
excreted benzene on the vertical axis.
The further up it goes, the better.
Again, the horizontal axis is the time
passed. And there's four groups. And it
so turns out that the empty circle and
the empty squares indicate people who
are deficient in this gene and therefore
can't produce a functional GST1 enzyme,
which means that they excrete much less
of these pollutants than people who have
the enzyme. However, the green
conditions are the ones given the
broccoli sprout drink and see what
happens. They not only normalize their
benzene excretion, but surpass people
who have the enzyme and don't drink the
detox drink. How incredible is that?
Still, two things to say here before we
finish things off. One, notice how these
people still excrete some of these
pollutants. How is that possible if they
don't have the enzyme? It's possible
because there are other versions called
isoforms of the enzyme. So while they
don't have all the versions, they have
other versions and the green drink of
life as I shall hence call it can
stimulate these enzymes as well as
described previously with the general
GST enzyme. Two, the people with the
primary enzyme still have an advantage.
So in any scenario, drinking the green
drink of life shall benefit all
immensely. Although there are still
advantages to not being genetically
mutilated, you still hold a special
place in my
heart. In the end, daily drinking a
sulurophane filled drink with will
enhance your elimination of carcinogenic
and other health harming molecules, even
if your genetics may be battling against
you through a lack of this GST1 enzyme.
Now, as for another detox pollutantfree
video going over ways to improve your
wasteland of a body, you may want to
consider this upcoming video right here.
I'll see you over there.